hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today we are
going to learn about a new way of
embedding the controls inside a
particular object inside Tosca
and there are different ways of doing
this uh we'll see how you can embed
controls inside a table object but this
could be applied to any other object
type when you are working with a web
application
okay so the scenario which I picked is
this obstacle course from try centers
and here you can see this is a table
with different rows and columns and then
there is a control here a button which
is inside this particular table and it
has got this for each and every row
right so what I want to do here is I
want to click on this go for it button
in the first row okay or maybe any row I
like right so this is an embedded
control inside this table and I want to
click on this okay so it's not that you
can do it straight away by just scanning
it and then clicking on it because all
these controls are similar right so they
will have the same properties so there
has to be a way of clicking just this
particular button now we know there are
different ways of doing it you can use
index you can use the table sharing
methods to click on this particular
button right but we'll see uh how the
control is basically separated from the
table controls and that is where we want
to embed this control uh into the module
or into the table okay inside the module
so let's see how we can do this
so first let me go ahead and scan this
particular module and then let me
explain uh you how this embed control
looks like so automatically uh Tosca is
not going to add it as an embedded
control okay so uh it will show it as a
separate control so if you see here
uh in this table so this is the table
which contains all the different rows
and rows and columns right
and we need to select this table okay to
access all these controls and then you
will see these links which is go for it
right so all these links are for
different rows and if I increase this
filtered items you can see it properly
okay so you can see now the TR which is
the table row has got the go for it link
right but uh it's not best practice to
directly select the table row okay and
then select the go for it still it won't
be a embedded control okay
so for now if I go ahead and maybe
select this first link okay
so Tosca will say that it is not a
unique control right so that's fine
um obviously I can change some technical
properties to make it unique or use the
index right but we don't want to go uh
in that path we want to see a different
way of doing this okay so for now I'm
going to save this module
okay
and let's go back here
and this is our module right
so this is the obstacle list module and
let me rename this
and here you will see that this is the
table and it has got the rows and
columns but the link is not inside that
particular row okay so when I go ahead
and I've created a test case folder and
a test case okay just for this demo and
if I go ahead and add this module here
um so you will see that it's not inside
the particular cell right so that should
be the ideal way because it's an
embedded control inside each row this
particular link is present right so if I
have selected the first link and I go
ahead and click on this or perform the
click method if I execute this uh it's
going to fail okay and the reason is
pretty simple there are multiple
controls with the same properties so
it's not going to uh click on a
particular button because it's not able
to uniquely identify it okay so we'll
see that error once this test case fails
and then we'll see
um how we can basically fix this error
okay
so now you can see the test cases failed
and it will also show the log info as
more than one control found for this
action go for it and that's why it was
not able to click on this okay so that
was on expected lines okay it was
supposed to fail
but let's now see how we can fix this
easily okay so how we can make this go
for it link as an embedded control for
that particular row so that we can steer
that particular control from the table
row itself okay
so for that I'm going back to my module
here you can see and I want this
particular link inside this particular
cell right because uh it's inside the
first row you can see and inside this is
the cell okay table cell
so uh what you can do is to make it a
embedded control you can just drag this
particular link inside and put it inside
this cell okay
so now if you see uh the table the row
and then inside the cell we have got the
link so it has become now embedded
control inside the table row itself okay
so now if I go ahead and delete this and
again drag this module into the test
case
so now if I go into the test case you
will see that it has got this particular
cell okay inside the cell we have got
the control
and now I can go ahead and click on it
but first I will select the first row
and then I will select the respective
cell so this is the action cell okay
which contains this particular link
and here I'm going to change it to
select
okay and then I'm going to click on it
so this way you can embed a control
inside a particular table cell and then
perform the necessary operation okay so
now if I go ahead and run this this time
it will be able to click on that
particular link inside the table itself
okay
so as you can see it has clicked on the
first obstacle go for it and it has
reached this page right
so this was the first way of doing this
just dragging the control inside the
particular cell or particular object
right so you can embed that particular
control uh using this way
the other way around is
so say for example we don't have this
particular control we have not scanned
it right so last time we scanned this
explicitly this particular control but
if I go ahead and remove this okay
and right now I've just got a table
which I have scanned okay on this
particular page
so now what we can do is we can create
our own embedded control inside a
particular table row cell okay so if I
go inside this cable row and then cell I
right click on it and then you go into
this three ellipses expand this and then
you will see here there are different
controls okay now depending on what type
of control you want to create you can
select that particular control okay so
for me uh that particular control is a
link so I'll be clicking on this create
embedded link control okay
and then I can put a name here say I put
it go
okay now this is going to work because
uh there is only single
Link in this particular table row okay
but if there are multiple uh
multiple controls like two links or two
buttons then if you don't add any
particular properties right technical
properties for this particular control
which you have created uh it won't work
so everything will have the same
properties so it's pretty ideal and a
best practice so whenever you are
creating an embedded control you should
be creating or adding uh new technical
properties for it at least the ones you
know okay
so for that again if we can go to the
properties here okay and right click on
this again go to that three ellipses and
expand it and there you will find create
technical ID parameter okay so I'm going
to click on this I'm going to add some
technical properties right
so here I know that the tag value is a
because it is a link okay
and then I can add another one although
it's optional I can add the inner text
okay and for this I know it is the text
go for it
okay so this way I can make sure that
this particular link is getting
identified by Tosca using this technical
properties which I have added okay so if
you have got multiple controls which
have got the same properties and you are
adding another embedded control which is
pretty similar then try to make it
unique using this additional technical
properties which you can add on your
control okay
so even without scanning a particular
control I can add my own embedded
control and then I can use it inside my
test case okay
so now that we have added uh the
embedded control and the additional
technical properties let's go ahead and
add this module into the test case and
let's see if it can still work the same
way okay so we'll steer it in a similar
way I will select the first row I will
select the cell which is action uh we'll
change the action mode to select
and then for go you need to type the
click method okay so by default you
won't get it because it is a custom
embedded control so we need to type the
value as click okay
let's go ahead and execute this now
and you can see that it is still
clicking on the first row for that
particular link which is go for it okay
so this way you can add your own custom
embedded control into a particular table
row cell or basically any other object
type which you are currently working on
okay so I've shown you both the ways uh
one is the simple way you scan it and
then you drag and drop it and the other
way is you don't even need to scan that
particular control you can add a custom
control uh as an embedded control into
that particular object okay
so that's all for this video uh I hope
uh you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today if you have not
already subscribed to our channel do
subscribe as we are coming up with lots
of more interesting videos on Tosca and
many other different automation tools
so until the next video keep watching
and keep learning Tosca